あ…。
After Gon parts ways with Killua
in order to stop the selection, he finds himself under attack
by new Chimera Ants.
知らんぷり
An owl and a bat?
そうだ　あいつなら ゴンを気に入ってるから
They're both nocturnal creatures...
何とかしてくれるかも ん？　あ！
Hunters of the night! From the left?
アホ！
Bring it!
何だ？ 顔見知りでもいたのか？ あ　いやぁ…。
The owl's feathers? Damn...
あっ。 あの時の女！ 何だ　シズクの知り合いか？
The bat's wings are so loud,
I can't hear the owl at all!
もう一度。
If the owl is acting in a support role, I should focus on the sound of the bat's wings.
レディ…　ゴー！
Right after the owl attacks,
the bat will attack! Now!
もう一度。
Damn, I missed again?
レディ…　ゴー！
Bah, he's correctly guessing
the direction of my attacks.
うぐ…。
For a human, his ears are sharp.
なぁ…　俺ぁ　「クモ」の中で
And his aura keeps growing, so my feathers aren't doing any damage.
腕相撲　何番目に強えぇかなぁ？ ７８番ってとこじゃねえか？
The bat uses ultrasonic waves to
anticipate the timing of my attack.
弱くもないけど 強くもないよね。
Unless I find a way to stop it, I can't win!
でよ　一番強いのが ウボォーギンって男だったんだが
First comes rock...
こいつが鎖野郎に やられたらしくてな。
His aura continues to grow.
だから　そんな奴 知らないって言ってるだろ！
This could pose a problem. Not at all...
ガキ！
This is our chance. He's probably using his ultimate attack.
次に許可なく喋ったら…
If we can evade it, we've won.
ぶっ殺すぞ。
I can use my ultrasonic waves
to see it in advance.
もう一度。
Wait, I'll try getting closer as quietly as I can.
レディ…　ゴー！
The sound's moving away.
竹を割ったような ガチンコ好きの単細胞だ。 その反面　時間にうるさくてよぉ よく遅刻が原因で
The sound's gone! Now, with no wingbeats...
俺やフランクリンと ケンカになったが
I dive! That won't work!
俺は　素の殴り合いじゃ ボコられっぱなしだった。
Your wings aren't like the owl's,
so I can hear you slice through the air.
「旅団」設立前からの付き合いだ。
Now, show me your ultimate attack.
誰よりも知ってる。
He isn't acting?
あいつが…　ウボォーが…
I guess a human can only hear so much.
戦って負けるわけがねえ！
In that case, I'll make my move... I'll slash your jugular!
汚ねぇ罠にかけられたに 決まってる！
Keep my motions minimal.
絶対に許さねえ。
Wait until I draw her as near as possible!
何人　ぶっ殺してでも捜し出す。
He was baiting me? I'm in trouble. But his punch will take a
few milliseconds to land.
鎖野郎は 俺達に強い恨みを持っている。
I have plenty of time to fly away!
「旅団」に恨み？ 最近　雇われた？
The noise...
ハッ
I can't see.
直接　知らなくても 噂で聞いたりしてねえか!?
I must get away! You won't escape!
よく思い出せ！
Rock...
心当たりがあったら隠さず喋れ！
You aren't the only one that can use sound... Paper... ...to locate others.
知らないね！ たとえ知っていても
Paper!
お前らなんかに教えるもんか！
All right.
血も涙もない連中だと 思ってたけど
A rock?
仲間のために泣けるんだね。
He used that to deflect my shot?
だったら　その気持を
That was close... Damn it!
ほんの少し… ほんの少しでいいから
I used my special attack and
still couldn't bring it down!
お前　調子乗り過ぎね。
Is this ultrasound, too?
うっ！ ゴン！
That stupid kid has a loud voice...
うっ…。
But I'm much better at attacking with sound!
動くと切る。
This is the true power of their combination.
質問に答えるね 鎖野郎を知らないか？
They strike with sound and finish with brawn. What now?
言っただろ　お前らに 教えることなんか　一つもない！
Do I cover my ears? No, I can't...
フッ…。
In the darkness, if I handicap my hearing,
my reaction time will suffer.
フェイタン
I know! Gyo!
やめろ。 何をやめるか？
His eyes are shining?
お前が　やろうとしてることだ。
Or is that aura?
私がやること お前　分かるのか？
He'll rely on his eyes, ignoring sound? Let's give him another...
腕　へし折る気だろ。 初めは指ね　軽く爪　剥ぐ。
Secret Noise!
おい　やめとけ　ノブナガ。 ルールは忘れてないだろうね。
Water significantly weakens the power of sound!
団員同士のマジギレ　ご法度だよ。 分かってるよ！
Good, this is better...
もめたらコインだろ！
I can locate the owl through its aura.
裏。 表！
A feather?
表だ　放してやれ。
Of course... They started off as wild animals.
で　どうすんの？　この２人。
when approaching their prey!
まだ鎖野郎のこと 聞き出せてないんでしょ？
I can fend off their attacks,
but the ultrasound really hurts.
知らねえなら 解放してやればいいさ。 どうだ？　パクノダ。
If I don't keep up the Gyo, they'll take me down before
I can even find them!
２人とも 本当に心当たりはないわね。
In terms of latent aura,
the kid has a clear advantage.
ホント？ ええ。
Even after being hit all those times,
he's taken no damage.
彼らに鎖野郎の記憶はないわ。
But his level of capability is irrelevant.
珍しく外れたな　お前の勘。
Without a strategy, he's just a moving target.
おかしいね。
They work in perfect sync.
まっ　パクノダが言うなら 間違いないだろうけど。
I have to disrupt that!
おい　ゴン ここに来る時　何か　されたか？
If I use Rock, I can defeat this one.
ううん　質問されただけだよ。 だよな…。
But then the bat might run
and warn the other Ants!
俺達に気づかれずに 調べたってことか？ 何を？　どうやって？
To me, a starry night is as bright as day.
奴らの様子からして パクノダって女の調査は かなり信頼されている
As long as I'm not in total darkness, I can see you without needing
to rely on my hearing!
勘以上の説得力を持った方法
So if I cover my ears... I can attack at will!
記憶？ ((あんた　どう？ 心当たりない？))
The kid has shrouded his entire
body in aura to avoid damage.
記憶を探る能力!? 対象者に触れることで!? だとすると合点が行く
But that reduces the strength of his attacks,
making it impossible to stand against them.
そして　ヤバい 確かに　あの時点では
At this rate, he'll never defeat them...
鎖野郎に 心当たりなんてなかった
It's over for this kid.
でも　今は 連想してしまっている
Their weakness is that
もう一度　調べられたら…
their movements are always in sync!
鎖野郎と関係ないなら 帰していいんじゃねえか？
Here!
いや　関係ないとは 言い切れない。
to avoid both being targeted at once.
後ろで糸を引いている奴が いるはずだ。 もし鎖野郎が　普段 鎖を身に着けてなかったら？
When the owl is in front of me, the bat is directly behind me!
この２人が　鎖野郎と認識してない だけかもしれないだろ？ 解放するのは 黒幕を吐かせてからのほうが
A giant wall?
そいつは鎖野郎じゃないよ。
The real wall was
彼は 単独で行動しているはずだから。
behind me...
ノストラードファミリーを通じて 情報は　いくらでも入って来る。 一応　鎖野郎は 組に所属してるわけだからね。
He turned our teamwork against us?
俺達の標的は　鎖野郎だけだ。 それ以外は　ほうっておけばいい。
If I only have one opponent,
I can concentrate on attacking.
だそうだ…　よかったな。
Once he pulls off one plan,
things will go his way...
ベェ！ いや　ダメだ！
But that attack won't be enough
to get him anywhere here.
そいつは帰さねえ。
Damn!
坊ず　「クモ」に入れよ。 俺と組もうぜ？
First comes rock... Rock... Paper...
やだ！　お前らの 仲間になるくらいなら
Why, you...
死んだほうがマシだ！
Rock!
ヒヒヒ…　随分　嫌われたなぁ。 おめぇ　強化系だろ？
I made sure to knock you west!
だったら　何だ！
Go back to NGL!
やっぱり　そうだよ！
That was incredibly strong...
クフフ…　アッハッハッハッ…！
I see... This is his real ultimate attack.
フフフフフフ！
I take back what I said. This kid can be useful.
よう！　団長が戻るまで こいつら　ここに置いとくぞ。
But how do I proceed?
入団を推薦する！
Diego has been dethroned.
本気かよ。 団長が認めるはずないね。
Brainwashed soldiers are running around,
slaughtering entire villages and towns!
まぁ　いいけど 見張りは　あんた１人でやりなよ。
Diego has fallen? Is that true?
逃げても　私らは知らないよ。
But we all saw the soldiers try to kill everyone.
似てる？ ウボォーとあの子が？ ああ 感情丸出しのとことか
Warn people in other areas!
怒ると 後先　考えなくなるとことか。
Who's interfering?
何より　そっくりなのが　他人事で 一番　力を発揮するとこか。
It was in the southeast this time. Some of my puppets have been stopped. That was fast.
あいつは １対１で戦うことを好んだが
Whoever they are, they're keeping
low and unpredictable.
一番強いのは　ノブナガと組んで 大勢と戦う時だったからな。
An assassin? But they are acting on their own... A decoy?
守るもんがあったほうが あいつにとってはいいんだ。
This is so annoying...
足手まといがいると 強くなるってことね。
I wanna kill them!
逆にノブナガの能力は タイマン専門っていうか
Which means we cannot go. You think?
限定条件つきみてぇなとこ あるからな。
But it doesn't feel like the purpose is to bait us.
ケンカのたびに　２人は組まされて ブたれてたが
They're being careful not to let me catch them...
まんざらでもなさそうだった。 はい　思い出話は そこまで！　こっから本題だ。
It may all be an act to draw you out. But perhaps I'm over-thinking things.
これは ハンターサイトで入手した
But... But...
ノストラードファミリー 構成員リストだ。
Ah, how I long to indulge myself
in the delight of agonizing...
ボディーガードとして　組長の娘に ついているらしいんだが
It is the sweet trap of the thought process.
ウボォーをさらったのは こいつらだ。
Nothing more. The answer is simple.
鎖野郎の見た目が分からない以上 知ってる奴を見つけるしかない。 あっ　こいつ　俺が殺った 左上の奴　ペケつけといてくれ。
We can let the other Ants handle the rest.
引き続きペアで行動し
Is it our turn?
リストの人物捜しに 全力を挙げてくれ。
When we were injured and on the run from the Hunters, you took us in.
じゃ　午後１０時に ここに集合ってことで！　以上。
You even gave us instruction on using our power.
ちょっと！ ノブナガは留守番だろ？
It is time for us to return the favor!
誰か余った奴と組みなよ。
Someone's running around
and disabling my puppets.
ウフ。
Can you kill them?
痛てて。
I'll give you updates on their location.
甘かった… 俺が　あの場面で動いたら
Understood.
ヒソカは　ためらわず 俺を殺す気だった あの殺気…　動けなかった
Can we really trust them?
もし　ゴンが　あそこで 致命傷を負わされかけたら
Nah, I don't trust them.
そしたら　俺は動けたかな？ )
They're the ones trying to earn our trust, so they'll try hard to carry out their mission.
((お前は　人というものを 殺せるか殺せないかでしか 判断できない))
It's possible that they're looking for an
opportunity to stab us in the back.
違う ((「勝ち目のない敵とは戦うな」 俺が　口を酸っぱくして 教えたよね？))
In that case, we should treat them accordingly.
違う！
The closest village is at two o'clock.
フッ　おっかねぇなぁ。 殺す気満々って面だぜ。
Should I skip them and head for
Taba, forty kilometers away?
先に言っとくが
Play it safe...
俺の間合いに入ったら斬るぜ。
Don't let anyone find me.
くっ！
What's wrong? As we speak, Cheetu is racing
toward East Gorteau.
まともに　やり合うのは無理だ
It seems the Hunters that replaced
us failed to capture him.
何とか逃げる方法を考えよう 窓は　なし
Is he headed toward us? No, if he continues on his current
course, he'll pass far to the south.
出口は１つ
Where are you going?
どうやって　あいつを 出口から遠ざけるか…
Don't try to stop me... I'm already in a bad mood.
レオリオのほうは 大丈夫かなぁ？
The Hunter Association has captured three
hundred and nineteen Chimera Ants
うまくゼパイルさんと 合流できてるといいけど。
outside of NGL as of yesterday.
ん…。 キルア　大丈夫？
But Colt confirmed that none of
them were Squadron Leaders.
ああ…。
According to him, there are eight Squadron Leaders left
that would be considered aggressive.
ねぇ　ゼパイルさんに 教えてもらったのって
Hunters have encountered four,
but they all got away.
「ヤキヅケ」と「ヒラキ」と… あと何だっけ？
Cheetu is coming to East Gorteau for a reason.
忘れた。
He must know the King is here.
「ヨコヅケ」だったっけな？ 何か違う気がするなぁ。 ゴン。 ん？
He's choosing to return to the King's
service in order to increase his power.
俺が囮になる。 その隙に　お前だけでも逃げろ。
My ability is still in effect,
and I have more raw strength.
何言ってんだ！ まったくだ　やめとけ。
But if we let him slip away and
he gains even more power, there's no telling who will win next time.
敵の力量が分からねえほど 未熟でもあるめぇ。 隙なんか　つくらねえよ。 分かってるよ！　そんなこと
If we allow more Ants like him to join the King, we'll never be able to draw the Royal Guard away.
出口が１つしかない 見通しのいい部屋
Are you still gonna try to stop me? Eh?
こちらの言動は筒抜け
If you are, I'll fight you first.
一分の隙も見せずに 俺達を監視する敵
First, we contact Morel-san.
恐らく居合の達人であろう 奴の初太刀における間合いは 俺の倍以上は　ある そこに踏み込めば 致命傷は確実
If worse comes to worst,
he'll need to replace us. I'll come with you.
だからこそ意味があるんだ！ )
This should increase the odds
of capturing that Ant.
やってみなきゃ分かんねえだろ！
It's Knuckle... Something's come up. Yes, I'd guess so.
キルア　何　考えてんだ!?
Probably. Yes. So, uh...
あいつの初太刀は 俺が死んでも止めるから
Hello? Hello?
その間に逃げろっつってんだよ！
Fools!
はぁ!?
I told you to send Riakke!
何しやがんだ　てめぇ！ 勝手なこと言うな！ あぁ!?
He'd have been perfect for this.
死ぬとか 簡単に言うなって言ってんだ！
Huh?! I don't give a damn!
んだと！　おめぇだって さっき言ってただろうが！ 俺は　いいんだ！ でもキルアはダメだ！
What's wrong? The Chimera Ant we were tracking escaped.
はぁ？ ハハハ…！
The review board didn't send
the Hunter we requested!
強化系にゃ 理屈が通用しねえんだよなぁ。
Who did they send? Some Hunter I've never heard of.
死ぬ気でやらなきゃ　こっから 逃げられっこねえんだよ　バカ！
Probably an Association dog. An Association dog...
ひとの気も知らないで　勝手なこと 言ってんのは　どっちだよ！
You mean Hunters who only take jobs
through the Hunter Association.
あ　知んないね！　バカだもん！ ガッハハ　ハハハ…！
It isn't surprising that they have less talent.
やっぱり おめぇら　おもしれぇわ！
Damn! I should have gone
to talk to Riakke myself!
なぁ　悪いようには　しねえ おとなしくしとけ。
Don't be foolish!
お前が本気なのは　よく分かってる 無駄死にするな。
If you do anything without board approval, the Chairman will get all the grief.
団長が戻るまでの辛抱だ。 そこで団長のお眼鏡に かなわなきゃ帰してやるよ。
He had to argue with the executive
committee just to get the two of us here.
だが ここで逃がすくらいなら斬る。
But they don't understand the situation.
俺に刀を抜かせるな。 俺が抜けば　お前らは死ぬ。
They base it on past accomplishments
and donations to the Association...
あ…。 あっ　思い出した！
The review board has always been inflexible.
「ヨコヌキ」だよ　「ヨコヌキ」！ 「ヤキヅケ」と「ヒラキ」と
How can you be so relaxed?!
もう一つが「ヨコヌキ」！
If we underestimate the Squadron
Leaders, we'll pay dearly for it.
あっ。 思い出した？
They're strong.
ああ　思い出した　思い出した！
After all, they listen to their deepest desires.
ね！　こんな簡単なことに 気づかなかったなんて！ あ？
So they have the talent to quickly master
スッキリしたところで…。 行くか！ 本気か？　死ぬだけだぞ。
the abilities they need the most. If we let the review board bring self-preservation
and formality in, we won't get help in time.
こちとら 居合斬りを手加減するほど 器用でも　お人よしでもねえぞ。
Maybe that's their goal... You refer to the rumors that
the Vice-Chairman's faction
バカが！
controls the review board?
出口が　ふさがれてるなら… 別の所から出ればいい！
who agree to vote for him in the next election?
壁を…　チッ　どっちを追う？
There's no evidence of anything
like that happening.
ここは５階
You think they're stupid enough to get caught?
ツリ目のほうは すぐ隣が　もう階段
Look at the facts!
黒髪のほうだ！
They've let every Squadron Leader
they've faced escape alive!
これで　こっちから追い込めば 袋のネズミだ
If this expedition fails,
the Chairman will shoulder the blame.
奴らは壁をぶち抜いて 逃げられるんだ！
They're willing to do whatever it
takes to guarantee that result.
ツリ目は下に… やはり黒髪を追うしかねえ
As the Chimera Ants claim more victims, the voices calling for the Chairman's
resignation grow louder.
どこだ？　壁は壊れてねえし 入り口のドアも…
Too bad the voices belong to a bunch
of people sitting at their desks!
キルア！　いるか？ ああ！　いるぜ！
If we take out the King and five million
people are already dead, we've failed!
そうか！　最後の壁破りは囮！
We already knew that.
壁だけ壊して
The Chairman is prepared.
手前の部屋に隠れて 俺を　やり過ごし
When he developed this plan, he was
well aware of the consequences.
廊下に出た ２人で　あいつ　ぶっ倒すぞ！
He knew how long assuring victory would take, and the resulting casualties...
気配が消えた…　「絶」か
Five million is the low end... That's too high!
「纏」と「練」の高等応用技…
Marcos-san?
「円」！
The phones have been ringing nonstop!
通常は体の周囲 数ｍｍから数ｃｍの間隔で
Rumors of a coup d'état are flying around.
まとっているオーラを 自分の必要な間隔まで広げる
And it's been discovered that mass murders
are taking place all over the nation.
この「円」の中に潜む 刺客は　おろか
This is no rumor. It's actually happening!
舞い落ちる木の葉の数さえ 把握できる
What's going on here? Are you responsible for this?
いかに　お前らが気配を絶ち 音を消して近づこうと
We haven't done anything! The citizens have learned the
truth about the selection?
この中に入り込めば　即座に斬る
We'll discuss this later.
いつでも来い
Return to the office before anyone suspects you. Morel!
バカ！ チェっ　あいつ ぶっ飛ばしたかったのに…。
Our beloved leader, Diego, has an
urgent announcement to make.
絶対無理だって 返り討ちに遭って　あの世行き。 １００％？ 「念」の基礎しか知らない俺達の かなう相手じゃないね。
To ensure that our great leader's message
will be heard throughout the nation, we request that relay speakers in all
regions be turned to maximum volume.
ヘヘっ。 何だよ？ やっとキルアらしくなったじゃん！
All televisions and radios should be on,
and the volume raised to maximum.
むちゃを言うのは俺の役。 キルアは　それを クールに止めてくれなくちゃ。
Good evening, my beloved comrades.
フン…。 頼りにしてるんだから！ 勝手な奴！
I am Diego. I have just declared that East
Gorteau is under martial law.
で　どうする？　これから。 そりゃあ　何がしたいかによるさ。 俺　あいつら　ぶっ倒したい！
This precaution is being taken to combat
malcontents that would foment rebellion.
まぁ　そりゃ最初の趣旨から 外れちゃいないけどな。
I ask all comrades to stay indoors,
with your doors locked.
けど　そのためには 念能力の向上が必須だぜ。
Anyone outdoors without permission will
be identified as a rebel and punished.
奴らと対等に 渡り合えるだけの潜在能力が 「念」には　あるはずなんだ。
I ask that you not lend an ear
to false rumors being spread, but that you follow my instructions.
それを知るにはクラピカに聞くのが 一番　手っ取り早いんだけどな。 えっ　何で？ あいつらの仲間を倒したっていう 鎖野郎が　クラピカだからさ。
The soldiers of my special forces
will be visiting your residences, to see if any rebels are hiding inside.
え？ やっぱり気づいてなかったか。
Do not open your doors for anyone else.
本当なの？　それ。 十中八九な。
Their response was too fast.
もし　そうなら 俺達にもチャンスは　ある。
It must be Killua and Gon. They weren't supposed to act.
クラピカと同じ時期に 「念」を覚えたんだからな。
But this must be part of the Chimera Ants' plan.
俺達の資質に合った 俺達だけの能力。
They were so well-prepared,
I can't believe otherwise. The citizens learning the truth about
the selection wasn't important.
でも　それ以上に「旅団」と 同等以上に戦える能力が必要だ。
In fact, if they did, the military
would have an excuse to mobilize.
その答えのカギを握ってるのが クラピカってことか。 ああ。 その頃 ヨークシンの中心部では
East Gorteau has been placed under martial law, completely isolated from the rest of the world.